<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-01-23T17:38:45+11:00</updated><id>https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/</id><title>2016 CfA DTF Fellowship</title><subtitle>A small band of dedicated civic hackers making a difference to the way government works</subtitle><entry><title>CfA at Linux Conf Au 2017</title><link href="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-LCA_Wrapup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CfA at Linux Conf Au 2017" /><published>2017-01-23T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2017-01-23T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-LCA_Wrapup</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-LCA_Wrapup/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;23/01/2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image from “Planning Alerts, State Contracts then The World”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/LCA_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cfa-at-linux-conf&quot;&gt;CfA at Linux Conf&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week a couple of us fellows got to go to Linux Conf Au 2017 and present on the work we’ve been doing with the department over the past six months. Johan Codinha was presenting about the development of the “citizen scientist” in Australia and more specifically the &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeforaustralia.github.io/biodiversity/blog.html&quot;&gt;Victorian Biodiversity Atlas project&lt;/a&gt; he’s been working on at DELWP and was titled “Interface citizen scientists with government”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My presentation, titled “Planning Alerts, State Contracts then The World”, was about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://planningalerts.org.au/&quot;&gt;Planning Alerts&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openaustralia.org.au/&quot;&gt;Open Australia&lt;/a&gt; and how this influenced and inspired our project at the Department of Treasury and Finance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CfA stickers and flyers nestled in between FreeBSD and Drupal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/LCA_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;open-knowledge-miniconf&quot;&gt;Open Knowledge Miniconf&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Johan and myself were speakers in the Open Knowledge miniconf and ended up bracketing the event with Johan as the first speaker and myself as the last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Johan was Steven Ellis with a talk titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/ceYMBBiVfCE?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vgpwSN3UWxwyrtAm3b4NGb-&quot;&gt;“Almost Open - Just close the door behind you”&lt;/a&gt; where he discussed the changing dynamic of cultural forces exerted by the FOSS community on government and business. He encouraged us to try to get the government to simply acknowledge that they depend on and derive huge value from open source software already. For some reason governments seem unable to see (or publicly acknowledge) the benefits they already reap from open source in an eerily similar way that businesses were doing in the nineties and naughties. Steven also suggesting the financial benefits of FOSS to government such as the reduced maintenance costs by sharing the burden of support, negotiaion freedoms available due to a lack of vendor lock in and the benefits of a flourishing ecosystem feed by timely and effective access to data (read APIs). These benefits seem so obvious to those of us from the FOSS community that we forget that this might not be so obvious to a public servant for whom these are all new concepts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was then an interesting talk by Gavin Tapp on “How govCMS is part of the open government and open data movement in Government”. I was glad he included a brief outline of the lifespan of the Gov 2.0 taskforce that crystallised my understanding of how this initiative fits in with a lot of what we are doing. He mentioned an interesting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.finance.gov.au/sites/default/files/DoFD%20CMS%20Review%20Report%20-%20V2%202%20FINAL.pdf&quot;&gt;report comparing different CMS solutions&lt;/a&gt; performed by the federal treasury when considering GovCMS which I’m looking forward to browsing over sometime in the coming week. One thing he pointed out that was quite poingiant to me was that they did their best to discourage departments from requiring registration before accessing the data, unlike our project which now has all the information locked up tight… this is the opposite of open and transparent and does not set a good example for others to follow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch Steven Pousty presented &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Wm6JS3ATa1E?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vgpwSN3UWxwyrtAm3b4NGb-&quot;&gt;“Building My Own Little World with Open Data”&lt;/a&gt; where he discussed a data mapping and visualisation project comparing bird sightings and other environmental factors such as temperatures, seasons and tide levels. The CfA DELWP project even got a shout out for having similar data sets and interests in the common-boring-case being the most pertinent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cat Allman from Google then discussed &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Dq330EYbucg?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vgpwSN3UWxwyrtAm3b4NGb-&quot;&gt;“Open Meets Science @ Google”&lt;/a&gt; where she discussed Googles involvement in open source scientific tools and what they are doing to promote and educate the next generation of code-scientist hybrids. Software carpentry got a strong mention and is a movement I feel I should look into in Melbourne (and kick start a carpentry school if it’s not already here somewhere)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then after my talk Pia Waugh engaged us all in an ad lib conversation about the intersection of the FOSS societies and government culture. She encouraged us all to try to bestow the maker-mindset on public servants and open there eyes to techniques and capabilities they never knew they had (but had access to all along)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-2-keynote--law-and-policy-miniconf&quot;&gt;Day 2 Keynote &amp;amp; Law and Policy Miniconf&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was the Law and Policy miniconf and almost felt like a continuation of the Open Knowledge miniconf with most of the same faces and many related topics of interest. We also kicked off the day with a keynote by Pia Waugh titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/J6IqGuxCKa8?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vjU8DFL2K78ydGsrfz9Ty4O&quot;&gt;“Choose Your Own Adventure, Please!”&lt;/a&gt;. An important concept she covered was that the liberty we experience is dependant on the tools we can use, this is the “sufficiency” part of “free software being a necessary but not sufficient condition for liberty”. For example I’m “free” to build a house and (to a limited extent) I’m “free” to extend and modify my home… but in reality I’m not competent in the skills that would enable me to exercise those freedoms (carpentry, painting and so on). In the same way all the open source software in the world won’t help government servants if they are digitally illiterate and unable to capitalise the benefits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The miniconf kicked off with a “fishbowl discussion” on GPL Compliance. This fishbowl format was a new experience for me, the discussion began with five chairs at the front of the room and four audience members take four of the five chairs with the last one being left empty. These four kick off the discussion and any remaining audience members left with a question or comment can jump up and sit in the fifth chair, then one of the current people up the front have to concede their seat so that there is always a free chair for someone to take. This worked quite well because were were all a bunch of fussy, curious pushy para-legal-pedantic-nerds, but I fear it would suffer from the effect of amplifying already loud voices in some groups with more nominal cultures&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bradley Kuhn gave a presentation titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/C6HDJThJjyw?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vgX_uPVIWj6YEH5pqH9dJuJ&quot;&gt;“Beautiful Build: Releasing Linux Source Correctly”&lt;/a&gt; talking about his experiences encouraging GPL compliance and the finer definition of some simple terms such as “reasonably skilled”, “complete and corresponding source” and (I’m serious here) “the”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam Poultons talk “Decentralisation - Removing the Middle Man from Current Centralised Systems” touched on a few topics including the (surprisingly strong) relation between blockchain technology and stone currencies, how Twitter and Facebook are becoming our de-facto decentralised news sources and he also mentioned and explained the &lt;a href=&quot;https://voteflux.org/&quot;&gt;Flux party&lt;/a&gt; which has recently arisen in Australia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of Paul Foxworthy from seeing his visualizations of voter preferences in Australian elections. That aside, his talk titled &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/huk-m19ZEzI?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vgX_uPVIWj6YEH5pqH9dJuJ&quot;&gt;“Pushing on a Piece of String - OSIAs adventures in influencing governments”&lt;/a&gt; felt like he’d stolen the material from my inner most secret journal… except I don’t work for OSIA. During the talk he mentions that they had surveyed the ERPs being used by government and realised that over 200 unique and incompatible ERPs were being individually purchased when the government could use this extraordinary buying power to bargain for a better deal or at least compatible systems. Paul also stressed the immense savings that could be made by a government by embracing open machine readable standard formats and open source software to reduce costs of inevitable migrations and maintenance of information systems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pia Waugh then gave a talk on &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/2EuuhP6e6Rg?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vgX_uPVIWj6YEH5pqH9dJuJ&quot;&gt;“the relationship between openness and democracy”&lt;/a&gt; discussing the importance of openness and transparency as a prerequisite for democracy. “Democracy without openness always moves away from democracy”, Pia warns us and encourages us to remember that all the positive aspects of democracy are lost if we end up with a closed and opaque democracy… what use is it choosing your leader if you only have a choice of dictators, freedom is not sufficient, but it is necessary (where have I heard that before :p). One other choice moment during this impromptu talk was Pia riffing on people talking about government as a single monolithic monstrous entity, kind of like a Hydra. However those of us with hands on experience working with and for government understand it’s more like a pit of snakes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there was a panel on &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/_Kx8OJW6qho?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vgX_uPVIWj6YEH5pqH9dJuJ&quot;&gt;“The Future of Community Efforts to Protect FOSS using Legal Tools”&lt;/a&gt; run by Donna Benjamin which was a little less structured but still chock full of interesting tidbits, including the fact that Open Australia got resisted as an official charity by being a “Digital Library”. We also covered some topics related to foundations, not-for-profits and charities and the pressures and forces we need to balance to have successful organisations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final talk in the Law and Policy miniconf was &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/neXXomOOoYI?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vgX_uPVIWj6YEH5pqH9dJuJ&quot;&gt;“A Layperson’s Guide for Talking about Free Software Law”&lt;/a&gt; by Rikki Endsley who is an editor for opensource.com. It was an interesting talk from the internationalisation and globalisation perspective but not super relevant to our current predicaments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-bits-and-pices&quot;&gt;Other bits and pices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the conference continued to include material relevant to our work with government but also included talks from a broad spread of possible topics. Michael Cordovers talk on &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/AfX6MGKNC34?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vj42HSjrNXGFcA4bZ-ban1D&quot;&gt;“Future privacy”&lt;/a&gt; touched on the importance of anonymization and the lack of importance of actual names in modern identity managment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/7Js1PxZHjSo?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vj42HSjrNXGFcA4bZ-ban1D&quot;&gt;“Engaging with Open Data through Video Games”&lt;/a&gt; by the trio Paris Buttfield-Addison, Jon Manning and Tim Nugent had a few helpful tips on presenting an interesting an exciting hackathon project even if it’s not a game (and the importance of keeping it simple and keeping focused).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/R4SPny8FaAM?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vj42HSjrNXGFcA4bZ-ban1D&quot;&gt;“Why haven’t you licensed your project?”&lt;/a&gt; by Richard Fontana made me think that a role of “Licencing Zealot” at hackathons might not be as ridiculous as I’d first thought, there was also some food for thought about the post-open-source culture that has emerged over the past few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nat Dudley did an interesting (but almost entirely irrelevant) talk on &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/ZE4BNwBwYXw?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vj42HSjrNXGFcA4bZ-ban1D&quot;&gt;“Ada ❤️ Lace”&lt;/a&gt; and the role knitting played in the Belgium resistance movement, and more seriously the role a good community plays in an ecosystem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/6x-HYunGtR0?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vj42HSjrNXGFcA4bZ-ban1D&quot;&gt;“Handle Conflict, Like a Boss!”&lt;/a&gt; by Deb Nicholson was also in the “mostly irrelevant” basket, but included the hilarious example of conflicted interests in trying to run a “Dog &amp;amp; Boat Wash” business. Someone from the audience pointed out that they had seen a “Dog, Car &amp;amp; Boat Wash”… what a nightmare that would be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And speaking of nightmares, Timothy Terriberry gave a talk on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/lzPaldsmJbk?list=PLwGcrAT3m_vj42HSjrNXGFcA4bZ-ban1D&quot;&gt;“Progress in the Alliance for Open Media”&lt;/a&gt; discussing the ups and downs of negotiating with vendors of various kinds in establishing an open and shared media codec… and I thought government was a Kafkaesque nightmare :p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I have any time over the rest of the fellowship I’ll endeavour to cover more of the talks in greater depth and discuss them in relation to our project and CfA in general&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;videos-from-cfa-lca-talks&quot;&gt;Videos from CfA LCA talks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Network and Audio/Visual crews at LCA are just amazing and have already edited, mixed and mastered the LCA talks so they are available to download right now! This is incredible especially when put into context, remember that LCA is run by a non-profit organisation and run for the most part by volunteers, there are up to six simultaneous events, talks or workshops being run and recorded at any given moment, the events start at 9 in the morning and don’t wrap up until after 5. That’s 48 hours of footage a day, or about 240 hours of footage over the week and it was mostly up on Youtube by the time we all got into work on Monday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have achieved this by ruthlessly automating where possible, they use flexible systems that allow for simple assumptions and refinement and correcting later, placing great trust upon the volunteers (who have in many cases just learned to use a video capture system), empowering speakers to review and confirm their own work and pre-confirming any details possible prior to crunch time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could all learn a lot from the LCA A/V team… Thanks for another great year of memories LCA NOC &amp;amp; A/V&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Planning Alerts, State Contracts then The World&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qn5qyZksrSc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interface citizen scientists with government&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OXGr4KlQ05E&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My impression of what the other teams do&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/LCA_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary>23/01/2017</summary></entry><entry><title>Development OnLine</title><link href="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-OnLine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Development OnLine" /><published>2016-10-21T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2016-10-21T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-OnLine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-OnLine/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;21/10/2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Australian, Aborgional, Torres Strait Islander and Victorian flags flying out along the “second front” of Treasury&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Flags_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;online-now&quot;&gt;Online Now!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper prototypes have grown up and left the nest leaving us in charge of a couple of delinquent source code repositories and a belligerent Heroku instance. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CodeforAustralia/dtf-genesis&quot;&gt;source code repository&lt;/a&gt; has been up for a while now but new to the scene is our &lt;a href=&quot;http://dtf-genesis.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;live deployment to Heroku&lt;/a&gt;. We can’t say there haven’t been speed bumps along the way, but we are glad to have had any issues early in the project when we have a bit of time up our sleeves (and rebuilding the database is quicker at this point of the process)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;analytics-integrations-and-more&quot;&gt;Analytics Integrations and More&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have reconfigured the Analytics on the Genesis site to go through a service called Segment.io. The Segment.io service acts as a kind or duplicator and remailer for web analytics and switching to segment allows us to continue utilizing Google Analytics and at the same time experiment with a raft of other services such as Woopra, Tray.io and Treasure along with dozens of other data analysis and warehousing services&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;citylab-presentation&quot;&gt;CityLab Presentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melbourne City recently hosted us at the new CityLab venue on Bourke st for our second Open House event with Code for Australia and the other fellowship teams. Great to hear about the genesis of CityLab and the ongoing projects currently running in the space, but don’t take our word for it, here is the video of the introduction by Lorraine Tighe and Michelle Fitzgerald from CityLab with the mc on the day Alvaro kicking things off&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nTsvFNGdQyY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now here is our teams presentation on the code we’ve developed, how human focused design allows us to focus on the real issues and how web scraping may just save us all yet. Considered too hot for TreasuryNet so download now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0useXG_KkSY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;showcasing-our-mvp-at-dtf&quot;&gt;Showcasing our MVP at DTF&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a working minimum viable product we’ve been starting to show it off around the DTF and have even garnered some interest from people outside our own group. It’s been very rewarding getting feedback on the value of our outputs already. Another encouraging sign was that some people are already interested in using it and having it available as a resource for their day to day (or not so run of the mill) work. We were even able to capture this snap of a user “in the wild” trying out our tool and telling us what they want next&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/MVP_demo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary>21/10/2016</summary></entry><entry><title>User surveys and more and more prototypes</title><link href="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-User-Survey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="User surveys and more and more prototypes" /><published>2016-09-09T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2016-09-09T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-User-Survey</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-User-Survey/">&lt;!-- https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;20/09/2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wonderful time of the year to have a front garden like this&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Garden_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
![](/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Flags_1.jpg)
--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learning-to-let-go&quot;&gt;Learning to let go&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paper prototypes are dead, long live the paper prototypes. It’s sad but true, no sooner had we immortalized the prototypes by publishing them on the blog than we had to pack them up and file them away in the drawer marked “Excelent idea team, but now is not the time” :\ … however all is not lost, we’ve gained valuable insight into the DTFs desires and motivations by making them explain in clear language why some solutions are acceptable and others not&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were planning to mention that “We’ll be using rapid prototyping in our future work” about now but as you’ll see below, we already have. It has been a valuable method of digging down to the underlying emotions, requirements and desires of the client. It allows them to better visualize the underlying ideas behind a concept and makes it real and solid helping them to express why an idea might be genious/folly, what the like about it and even bring up related concepts they have had experiences with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;picking-up-new-tools&quot;&gt;Picking up new tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have setup Google Analytics on the teams web properties and while the results are not overly impressive at the moment we imagine that this will help us to focus our attention on the areas where it is most likely to have an impact&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Analytics_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;45%&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Analytics_02.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;45%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Analytics_03.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;45%&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Analytics_04.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;45%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve also begun using a Trello board to help coordinate team activities and utilizing mind mapping software so that our brainstorming sessions can have a lasting impact&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_MindMap_01.svg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;back-to-the-prototypes-now-with-surveys&quot;&gt;Back to the Prototypes… now with surveys&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now with a new focus and a much broader user base we’ve been back at the whiteboard thrashing out ideas and concepts to be prototyped. We focused in on the valuable-achievable quadrant in a value-risk breakdown and came up with nine core features we could deliver within the time frame we have that could provide immediate value to DTF and the public at large&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than bore you by detailing each one and then send you off to do our survey we’ve embedded it right here so if you have a spare 15~20 minutes we’d be ever so gratefull if you’d fill it out and help guide the features you do/don’t want to see and have a &lt;b&gt;direct effect&lt;/b&gt; on this &lt;b&gt;democracy&lt;/b&gt; of ours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf8YHYE3LzU4R7QOCRocP2MMeLOZpYG6dSIBxcfi1uhgYPZ4Q/viewform?embedded=true&quot; width=&quot;760&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a link to the survey ready to be tweeted to the world:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Help provide feedback to the Vic Gov and @CodeforAus about public contracting data https://goo.gl/forms/m2IHygbsbgZHwyRd2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-another-wrap&quot;&gt;Thats another wrap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time feel free to send any &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;omments, &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;orrections, &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;oncerns, &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;omplaints or anything else beginning with the letter &lt;strong&gt;“C”&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#050;&amp;#048;&amp;#049;&amp;#054;&amp;#045;&amp;#100;&amp;#116;&amp;#102;&amp;#045;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#119;&amp;#115;&amp;#104;&amp;#105;&amp;#112;&amp;#064;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#102;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#097;&amp;#117;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#114;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#105;&amp;#097;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&quot;&gt;DTF Project Feedback&lt;/a&gt;… that is if you don’t feel like leaving a comment below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finish off this blog with a photo of one of the the meetings we’ve been told that we’re not allowed to attend (… and yet they keep having it withing earshot of our cubicles #YourMoneyHardAtWork)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_SecretMeeting_01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary>20/09/2016</summary></entry><entry><title>Prototyping at DTF</title><link href="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-Prototypes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prototyping at DTF" /><published>2016-09-05T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2016-09-05T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-Prototypes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-Prototypes/">&lt;!-- https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;05/09/2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Australian, Aborigional, Torres Straits and Victorian flags fly over the DTFs front door&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Flags_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
![](/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Flags_1.jpg)
![](/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Garden_1.jpg)
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prototypes-prototypes-and-more-prototypes&quot;&gt;Prototypes, prototypes and more prototypes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week at the Department we’ve been brainstorming some concepts about how to improve the quality and frequency of reporting by other government departments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we are still yet to gain access to any actual users of our systems we have begun creating &lt;strong&gt;paper prototypes&lt;/strong&gt; of potential solutions and showing them to users with a similar perspective and members of the general public&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below we will detail all of the designs, both epic-survivor and fail-whale to discuss some of there pros and cons. The opinions and ideas expressed below are a mix of all the above mentioned stakeholders liberally mixed with my own biases and forgetfulness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can click on the icons below to see the full sized images and leave a comment below if any catch your fancy (or make you ill)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto01---autofilljpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto01---autofilljpg-01---autofill-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_01 - autofill.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_01 - autofill.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #01 - Autofill prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple idea of using DTF and other public data to auto populate fields in the form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This prototype provoked the best stakeholder comment of the day… “Isn’t this what you’re doing?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this is a fairly common form technique and one we are assuming we will use, we still wanted to put it in front of our users and get feedback on exceptions to the rule or any little caveats they may think might apply to this form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular we were warned to &lt;strong&gt;be careful&lt;/strong&gt; with geographic boundaries of &lt;strong&gt;municipalities&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;post-codes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also cases where we want to &lt;strong&gt;encourage thinking&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;observing&lt;/strong&gt; over just getting it done quick. In some of these cases we may want to consider not autofilling some fields even if we can&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto02---last-responsejpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto02---last-responsejpg-02---lastfill-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_02 - last response.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_02 - last response.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #02 - Lastfill prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept fills in the form with the last used answers in a distinct color, fields can be updated or left with the defaults&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the prototype was rejected as it might encourage less thinking about responses, there were some insights gleaned in any case&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly was a feature we’d not considered, an &lt;strong&gt;audit trail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally there may be some cases where &lt;strong&gt;highlighting&lt;/strong&gt; (or &lt;strong&gt;red flagging&lt;/strong&gt;) variations or changes to the status of a project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto03---saved-fieldsjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto03---saved-fieldsjpg-03---saved-fields-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_03 - saved fields.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_03 - saved fields.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #03 - Saved fields prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept is to save the most commonly used options in a drop down or combo list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might be handy for some fields, but is also likely to promote no-thinking submissions, probably a &lt;strong&gt;no no&lt;/strong&gt; in most situations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto04---feedbackjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto04---feedbackjpg-04---fast-feedback-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_04 - feedback.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_04 - feedback.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #04 - Fast feedback prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept alerts users to issues in the form and prompts the DTF for prompt action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The confirmation of completion model was very well received although the DTF will not be contacting any departments without an explicit request&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red flagging&lt;/strong&gt; incomplete fields would also be a good feature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validation of form data&lt;/strong&gt; like the current excel trials could also be a good feature&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto05---savingjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto05---savingjpg-05---saved-progress-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_05 - saving.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_05 - saving.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #05 - Saved progress prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of saving (maybe with login or maybe on local storage) a form in a half completed state&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving progress is a &lt;strong&gt;must have&lt;/strong&gt; as the form may take some time to complete&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple &lt;strong&gt;background saving&lt;/strong&gt; would be the best mode and the ability to &lt;strong&gt;export to pdf&lt;/strong&gt; would also be appreciated&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto06---multidimentionaljpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto06---multidimentionaljpg-06---multidementional-input-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_06 - multidimentional.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_06 - multidimentional.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #06 - Multidementional input prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow for a more fluid or human feel by replacing radio buttons with two dimentional graphs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multidimensional inputs were thoroughly derided (thankfully) as were &lt;strong&gt;any&lt;/strong&gt; other &lt;strong&gt;attempts to fuzzify scoring&lt;/strong&gt; away from integers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto07---examplesjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto07---examplesjpg-07---examples-included-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_07 - examples.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_07 - examples.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #07 - Examples included prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept includes examples of what would constitute a score of a certain value in each field&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of including examples for users to refer to was also &lt;strong&gt;discouraged&lt;/strong&gt; as the DTF do not want to be seen to be dictating how departments score contractors&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This kind of implies that getting standardized scoring could be &lt;strong&gt;problematic&lt;/strong&gt; or at least &lt;strong&gt;difficult&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto08---workflowjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto08---workflowjpg-08---workflow-management-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_08 - workflow.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_08 - workflow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #08 - Workflow management prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This form has a backend to monitor the progress and dates of a contract and allert key people at the right moment or automate preprepared automated tasks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback suggests this would be useful in conjunction with &lt;strong&gt;reminders to kick start the process&lt;/strong&gt; after a waiting period&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks good and is &lt;strong&gt;worth showing&lt;/strong&gt; to the departments for further feedback&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto09---importjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto09---importjpg-09---importing-data-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_09 - import.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_09 - import.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #09 - Importing data prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept coould import much of the required data from a departments own CMS/otherMS/database/spreadsheets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were warned that departments might &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; have systems &lt;strong&gt;sophisticated enough&lt;/strong&gt; to export reports from, or those reports might contain insufficient data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any &lt;strong&gt;changes discovered&lt;/strong&gt; in static data should be &lt;strong&gt;flagged&lt;/strong&gt; and investigated&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also &lt;strong&gt;unlikely&lt;/strong&gt; that the departments would be &lt;strong&gt;wiling to share&lt;/strong&gt; internal reports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally the issue of &lt;strong&gt;who is going to pay&lt;/strong&gt; for all this came up during this prototype (although the question holds for any solution and is a factor we have so far only considered in passing)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto10---segmentedjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto10---segmentedjpg-10---segmented-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_10 - segmented.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_10 - segmented.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #10 - Segmented prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a build your own &lt;strike&gt;adventure&lt;/strike&gt; reporting form meta-form&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some employees will &lt;strong&gt;not like the idea&lt;/strong&gt; of building their own forms&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, all fields are &lt;strong&gt;mandatory&lt;/strong&gt; … maybe this is why no one gives much feedback now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto11---educationjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto11---educationjpg-11---educational-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_11 - education.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_11 - education.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #11 - Educational prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This prototype would include guidelines and educational material on how to assess the quality and performance of a construction project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;strong&gt;expand/collapse all&lt;/strong&gt; toggle would be essential, along with &lt;strong&gt;back to top&lt;/strong&gt; markers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise this one is a &lt;strong&gt;good idea&lt;/strong&gt; as long as it’s not done with hover tips&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto12---freeformjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto12---freeformjpg-12---freeform-reporting-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_12 - freeform.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_12 - freeform.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #12 - Freeform reporting prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a fun concept that came out of a group brainstorming session, just a field for the contract number and a whole world of opportunities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hell no! was approximately the feedback this prototype received… but if time allowed this just might grant significant insight into the issues, and wouldn’t you just love to see what came back&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto13---spreadsheetjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto13---spreadsheetjpg-13---spreadsheet-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_13 - spreadsheet.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_13 - spreadsheet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #13 - Spreadsheet prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept was to make people comfortable with spreadsheets feel right at home, the extra cells could be used for intermediate calculations with the locations of the final values the only predefined locations, this way the departments could build their own forms in a compatible way&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not very well received, but might still be an interesting final touch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto14---journeyjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto14---journeyjpg-14---journey-mapping-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_14 - journey.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_14 - journey.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #14 - Journey mapping prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This prototype allows a user to order the form as they wish and then provides visual indicators of progress and breadcrumbs for backtracking or skipping ahead&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This design was very &lt;strong&gt;well received&lt;/strong&gt; by our test audience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autosaving&lt;/strong&gt; is a must&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sections must not be able to be skipped&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto15---delegationjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto15---delegationjpg-15---delegation-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_15 - delegation.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_15 - delegation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #15 - Delegation prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This met-form concept makes it easy to delegate sub-components to any person or group, allowing for a collabrotive final report&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually this is performed by one person, but this would be &lt;strong&gt;great for two or more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education department in particular &lt;strong&gt;might be interested&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confidentiality concerns&lt;/strong&gt; for segments that might be sent out to external entities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto16---remindersjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto16---remindersjpg-16---reminders-and-alerts-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_16 - reminders.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_16 - reminders.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #16 - Reminders and alerts prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept is just for a system to monitor public contracting information and prompt departments that reporting on a contract is (over?) due&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reminders would be &lt;strong&gt;very worthwhile&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;detailing the reason&lt;/strong&gt; for the update/review would also be great&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worth discussing with Housing and other &lt;strong&gt;departments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people would have &lt;strong&gt;too many reports&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;summary&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;digest&lt;/strong&gt; might be more appropriate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Include links&lt;/strong&gt; to forms and resources&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More &lt;strong&gt;time for departments to plan&lt;/strong&gt; for reporting rather than reacting after the fact would be a great thing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto17---indirectjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto17---indirectjpg-17---indirect-scoring-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_17 - indirect.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_17 - indirect.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #17 - Indirect scoring prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept was to use multiple reviewers and utilise the wisdom of the crouds to use something like the mean values on the final report&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not well received as it involves &lt;strong&gt;duplication of effort&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However &lt;strong&gt;time based aggregation&lt;/strong&gt; might be useful for displaying &lt;strong&gt;sensitive information&lt;/strong&gt; to the public&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another idea might be to &lt;strong&gt;aggregate different classes&lt;/strong&gt; of reporting (such as department/contractor/public)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto18---analyticsjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto18---analyticsjpg-18---analytics-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_18 - analytics.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_18 - analytics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #18 - Analytics prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept was just to display a publicly visible dashboard of Victorian procurement reporting, allowing the public visibility so that they can exert pressure on departments to improve reporting to DTF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reporting to departments&lt;/strong&gt; on their reporting (gamification of the reporting process). Dep v Dep &lt;strong&gt;leaderboards&lt;/strong&gt;. Allow contractors to &lt;strong&gt;report on departments&lt;/strong&gt; too (allows them to exert pressure on departments to report better)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto19---flavoursjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto19---flavoursjpg-19---input-flavours-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_19 - flavours.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_19 - flavours.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #19 - Input flavours prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea allows users to flip between different styles of input for ratings for example from radio boxes, sliders, numeric text or some other method&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuzzy inputs might not help anything. Might lead to &lt;strong&gt;inconsistent&lt;/strong&gt; scoring&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto20---gamificationjpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto20---gamificationjpg-20---gamification-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_20 - gamification.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_20 - gamification.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #20 - Gamification prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept was to increase engagement by rewarding participation with points and harnessing the competitive nature of people by creating some kind of leaderboard of reported data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Positive feedback on &lt;strong&gt;both&lt;/strong&gt; aspects&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feedback also indicated a &lt;strong&gt;work-to-go&lt;/strong&gt; meter might be more pleasant than a work-done meter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto21---independancejpg-height120px-width120pxdtf-blogimagesprotosdtfproto21---independancejpg-21---data-independence-prototype&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_21 - independance.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/protos/DTF_Proto_21 - independance.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;120px&quot; width=&quot;120px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; #21 - Data independence prototype&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept allows departments to host there own solutions under the condition they provide an API to allow DTF to access the data it requires to evaluate performance on a contract&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could take the form of a simple API specification or an “out of the box” prerolled solution (something like a python server, postgresBD &amp;amp; custom DTF UI on a thumb-drive ready to rock a web-API)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review specific data will still need to be &lt;strong&gt;kept somewhere&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually data is &lt;strong&gt;locked up&lt;/strong&gt; in a CMS system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could use a &lt;strong&gt;shadow database&lt;/strong&gt; into which we dump the public aspects, then we can expose that without risk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auditability and &lt;strong&gt;traceability of data&lt;/strong&gt; then becomes an issue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requires &lt;strong&gt;work&lt;/strong&gt; to make data available, but would be very &lt;strong&gt;valuable&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;well-thats-all-for-now-kiddo&quot;&gt;Well, thats all for now kiddo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that the roundup of our current prototypes, hopefully we’ll have a few digitized versions for you to click on soon enough&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mean time feel free to send any &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;omments, &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;orrections, &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;oncerns, &lt;b&gt;C&lt;/b&gt;omplaints or anything else beginning with the letter &lt;strong&gt;“C”&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#050;&amp;#048;&amp;#049;&amp;#054;&amp;#045;&amp;#100;&amp;#116;&amp;#102;&amp;#045;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#119;&amp;#115;&amp;#104;&amp;#105;&amp;#112;&amp;#064;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#102;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#097;&amp;#117;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#114;&amp;#097;&amp;#108;&amp;#105;&amp;#097;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&quot;&gt;DTF Project Feedback&lt;/a&gt;… that is if you don’t feel like leaving a comment in our spiffy new comments section below telling us which ones you love and/or hate :D&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary>05/09/2016</summary></entry><entry><title>Our fellowship begins with DTF</title><link href="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-Start/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our fellowship begins with DTF" /><published>2016-08-26T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2016-08-26T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-Start</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-DTF-Start/">&lt;!-- https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;26/08/2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF-Disc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
![](/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Flags_1.jpg)
![](/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Flags_2.jpg)
![](/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Garden_1.jpg)
--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security-security-and-more-security&quot;&gt;Security, security and more security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is actually a bit heartening that security at the Department of Treasury and Finance is so tight, but as someone who just wants to get rapid traction on a short project it was rather frustrating how much of a blocker this was for our first week. In particular the lack of printing facilities was driving us crazy but things are improving and we even have limited access to the database they want us to work on. Only time will tell how difficult accessing other datastores and sources of contracting info is going to be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also in uncharted territory as the instructions provided so far have only given instructions for Mac or Windows… no mention of Linux! So far so good and it does seem like it’s going to be possible, but it will introduce an unwanted level of uncertainty to the situation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At least they’ve let us in and granted us access:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_office_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;purchasing-procurement-and-paying-for-stuff&quot;&gt;Purchasing, procurement and paying for stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three of our team has ramped up our understanding of the procurement process and related processes used at the DTF. It has been a great boon that all three of us come at the problem form different angles and have been able to assist each others learning and help clarify the groups understanding of the domain and the scope of the project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;agile-the-slow-way&quot;&gt;Agile the slow way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the structure of the workplace at the DTF and the stage of the project we are in it has been challenging to function as an Agile team and self direct our days agenda. The workplace has a low volume tolerance and so things like standups have to be taken into a meeting room, with the result that they can turn into drawn out meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment there are also key knowledge and influence holders we are having to meet with who we will have limited access to as the project progresses (yay) and this has also made any daily routines and rituals rather unstable. However we are starting to settle into a couple of rituals at regular times and I can see things getting better as we beginning being able to reach-out to people independently and set our own timetables&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Level 1: Chaos:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Ideas_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Level 1: Chaos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Level 2: Disorganized:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Ideas_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Level 3: Inspirational ideas for motivating better feedback:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Ideas_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototypes-and-place-holders&quot;&gt;Prototypes and place-holders&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naively prototyping the current form as is:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_BigForm.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week in addition to continuing our research into reporting practices and requirements we have begun prototyping some possible forms for our solution. Below are a selection of our ideas and prototypes we have been considering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper prototypes of possible form ideas:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Protos_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary>26/08/2016</summary></entry><entry><title>Our fellowship begins with CfA</title><link href="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-First-week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our fellowship begins with CfA" /><published>2016-08-08T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2016-08-08T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-First-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/DTF-Blog/Ben-First-week/">&lt;!-- https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/ --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;08/08/2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/images/CFA_day_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote of the day: &lt;strong&gt;“Build from the trenches… simplify from the overview”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first day we all got to know each other by doing a modified &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PechaKucha&quot;&gt;Pecha Kucha&lt;/a&gt; presentations. My biggest take-away from that was just how short 20 seconds is… but it was also great to get a glimpse into everyones little spark, what is it they just had to cram into 20 seconds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also did an interesting gamification workshop with Steffen Walz using his &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/playfuturedeck&quot;&gt;Future Deck&lt;/a&gt; strategy cards which reminded me of Enos &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oblique_Strategies&quot;&gt;Oblique strategy&lt;/a&gt; cards&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we discussed the importance of team agreements and the value of checkins and honest communication. We also discussed how shared understanding can help drive shared outcomes and conversely competing visions can often lead to divergent plans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-2&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote of the day: &lt;strong&gt;“Manually intensive internal process”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we discussed the importance in our role of demonstrating agile methods and design focused development for the government. We also covered how joint creativity and visioning exercises can help to highlight issues in current stakeholder discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had short presentations from the government officials involved in the three challenges. Since then I have found out that we are going to the Department of Treasury and so it seems that my mind has expunged the DWELP/Parks and Legal Aid challenges entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DTF challenge outlined a cumbersome system build for requirements long past… there were stories of databases migrating, the emailing of spreadsheets extracted from databases and the wailing and gnashing of… ok, maybe not the last one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally our solution would work alongside the Construction Supplier Register to promote better feedback from industry, increase transparency into the purchasing choices of the government and ideally assist in forecasting decisions for government procurement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also did a few visioning exercises as a group and as individual. I found it incredibly heartening to find that the most common thread between everyone in the group is that we all individually wanted to produce long term sustainable solutions that will persist beyond our fellowship. Unfortunately as a group our vision was a chaotic circus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-3&quot;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote of the day: &lt;strong&gt;“Nothing quotable is ever said on day three”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked with a mentor about the importance of following through in customer relations. Whilst it might not seem to be an overly insightful observation it is something that we, as technically minded people, can lose sight of. We must do our best to follow through on all our contacts requests and address them in a timely manner. We also discussed again the importance of lucid and real negotiation in agile. If we are not genuine, then we will fail to come to a genuine agreement. Part of being genuine is honestly being yourself, but the flipside is honestly listening&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 3 also saw our first challenge. The easy one. This challenge turned into a great example of our strength at rapid development of design and simplification of problems. All groups created a visible or even demonstrable prototype. While these prototypes had some rough edges that the department representatives could see, they all still represented real paths forward that could be tweaked and utilised to simplify the process by the end of the week or two (pending paperwork)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-4&quot;&gt;Day 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote of the day: &lt;strong&gt;“Why, why, why?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were spoilt with three guests on day 4 (including Guss from RHoK, who’m I’d thought I’d serendipitously bumped into downstairs) and we mostly talked about how defining the real problem is critical and often difficult. Playing the “why?, why?,why?” game can help but often we must go further than that and question the very problem we are looking at or broaden our stakeholder group&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also discussed &lt;a href=&quot;http://launchvic.org/&quot;&gt;Launch Vic&lt;/a&gt; which invests in infrastructure for start-ups, things like promoting the building of co-working spaces, encouraging the expansion of capacity of existing places or investing in shared infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had our second challenge in what we thought was a PTV form redesign. I read the problem, and I read it again. I looked up at my colleges and shrugged. They looked at me and shrugged… We all read it again. Finally someone broke the awkward silence: “what’s wrong with that?”… “nothing” we all replied. It was then that we made the fatal mistake… we assumed the role of the customer… when the customer was about 150 meters away at the nearest train station! Had we consulted with our stakeholders they would have told us that all the problems we saw with the system were non-existent… although what do we do at that stage: the right answer (which one team did) is: pivot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me about three days to think of the perfect way to pivot that problem that still keeps it relevant to the problem that the seniors ticket is suppose to solve. One of the benefits of the program is to make travel at non-peak times more attractive to seniors and so reduce the load on public transport during peak times. So I would investigate the feasibility of providing seniors a more comprehensive package that included reduced fares for travelling in non-peak times during weekdays in addition to the free weekend pass, further driving down peak demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-5-retro&quot;&gt;Day 5: Retro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote of the day: &lt;strong&gt;“As fast as things are now is as slow as they will ever be”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our final day we had a very enlightening discussion about the importance of designing with not only our users in mind but also the next generation. If our systems are to last they must be usable today and tomorrow… and tomorrow, that tomorrow might not look much like tomorrow does today&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also repeated the theme of finding the real problem, this time with an emphasis on visibility and making problems easy to find. Paint your problems red! There is also the possibility of using active agents to find problems, proactively creating autonomous entities that will seek out issues and conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our teams also self formed on Friday and obviously I was in the TDF team. It was very interesting to see the self formation process. I’d love to tell you more but it’s all secret agile retro business (which might be beer if you go on the slack messages)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll finish on a photo of lunch time discussions at TeamSquare level 4 with a few people from the DTF!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_lunch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary>08/08/2016</summary></entry></feed>
