<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-08-29T09:26:20+10:00</updated><id>/</id><title>2016 DTF Fellowship Team</title><subtitle>A small band of dedicated civic hackers making a difference to the way government works</subtitle><entry><title>Our fellowship begins with DTF</title><link href="/Ben-DTF-Start/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our fellowship begins with DTF" /><published>2016-08-26T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2016-08-26T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>/Ben-DTF-Start</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Ben-DTF-Start/">&lt;!-- https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF-Disc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
![](/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Flags_1.jpg)
![](/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Flags_2.jpg)
![](/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Garden_1.jpg)
--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security-security-and-more-security&quot;&gt;Security, security and more security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is actually a bit heartening that security at the Department of Treasury and Finance is so tight, but as someone who just wants to get rapid traction on a short project it was rather frustrating how much of a blocker this was for our first week. In particular the lack of printing facilities was driving us crazy but things are improving and we even have limited access to the database they want us to work on. Only time will tell how difficult accessing other datastores and sources of contracting info is going to be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also in uncharted territory as the instructions provided so far have only given instructions for Mac or Windows… no mention of Linux! So far so good and it does seem like it’s going to be possible, but it will introduce an unwanted level of uncertainty to the situation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At least they’ve let us in and granted us access:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_office_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;purchasing-procurement-and-paying-for-stuff&quot;&gt;Purchasing, procurement and paying for stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three of our team has ramped up our understanding of the procurement process and related processes used at the DTF. It has been a great boon that all three of us come at the problem form different angles and have been able to assist each others learning and help clarify the groups understanding of the domain and the scope of the project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;agile-the-slow-way&quot;&gt;Agile the slow way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the structure of the workplace at the DTF and the stage of the project we are in it has been challenging to function as an Agile team and self direct our days agenda. The workplace has a low volume tolerance and so things like standups have to be taken into a meeting room, with the result that they can turn into drawn out meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment there are also key knowledge and influence holders we are having to meet with who we will have limited access to as the project progresses (yay) and this has also made any daily routines and rituals rather unstable. However we are starting to settle into a couple of rituals at regular times and I can see things getting better as we beginning being able to reach-out to people independently and set our own timetables&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Level 1: Chaos:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Ideas_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Level 1: Chaos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Level 2: Disorganized:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Ideas_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Level 3: Inspirational ideas for motivating better feedback:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Ideas_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prototypes-and-place-holders&quot;&gt;Prototypes and place-holders&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Naively prototyping the current form as is:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_BigForm.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week in addition to continuing our research into reporting practices and requirements we have begun prototyping some possible forms for our solution. Below are a selection of our ideas and prototypes we have been considering&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paper prototypes of possible form ideas:&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_Protos_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary></summary></entry><entry><title>Our fellowship begins with CfA</title><link href="/Ben-First-week/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Our fellowship begins with CfA" /><published>2016-08-08T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2016-08-08T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>/Ben-First-week</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Ben-First-week/">&lt;!-- https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/images/CFA_day_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote of the day: &lt;strong&gt;“Build from the trenches… simplify from the overview”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the first day we all got to know each other by doing a modified &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PechaKucha&quot;&gt;Pecha Kucha&lt;/a&gt; presentations. My biggest take-away from that was just how short 20 seconds is… but it was also great to get a glimpse into everyones little spark, what is it they just had to cram into 20 seconds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also did an interesting gamification workshop with Steffen Walz using his &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/playfuturedeck&quot;&gt;Future Deck&lt;/a&gt; strategy cards which reminded me of Enos &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oblique_Strategies&quot;&gt;Oblique strategy&lt;/a&gt; cards&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we discussed the importance of team agreements and the value of checkins and honest communication. We also discussed how shared understanding can help drive shared outcomes and conversely competing visions can often lead to divergent plans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-2&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote of the day: &lt;strong&gt;“Manually intensive internal process”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we discussed the importance in our role of demonstrating agile methods and design focused development for the government. We also covered how joint creativity and visioning exercises can help to highlight issues in current stakeholder discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had short presentations from the government officials involved in the three challenges. Since then I have found out that we are going to the Department of Treasury and so it seems that my mind has expunged the DWELP/Parks and Legal Aid challenges entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DTF challenge outlined a cumbersome system build for requirements long past… there were stories of databases migrating, the emailing of spreadsheets extracted from databases and the wailing and gnashing of… ok, maybe not the last one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally our solution would work alongside the Construction Supplier Register to promote better feedback from industry, increase transparency into the purchasing choices of the government and ideally assist in forecasting decisions for government procurement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also did a few visioning exercises as a group and as individual. I found it incredibly heartening to find that the most common thread between everyone in the group is that we all individually wanted to produce long term sustainable solutions that will persist beyond our fellowship. Unfortunately as a group our vision was a chaotic circus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-3&quot;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote of the day: &lt;strong&gt;“Nothing quotable is ever said on day three”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked with a mentor about the importance of following through in customer relations. Whilst it might not seem to be an overly insightful observation it is something that we, as technically minded people, can lose sight of. We must do our best to follow through on all our contacts requests and address them in a timely manner. We also discussed again the importance of lucid and real negotiation in agile. If we are not genuine, then we will fail to come to a genuine agreement. Part of being genuine is honestly being yourself, but the flipside is honestly listening&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 3 also saw our first challenge. The easy one. This challenge turned into a great example of our strength at rapid development of design and simplification of problems. All groups created a visible or even demonstrable prototype. While these prototypes had some rough edges that the department representatives could see, they all still represented real paths forward that could be tweaked and utilised to simplify the process by the end of the week or two (pending paperwork)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-4&quot;&gt;Day 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote of the day: &lt;strong&gt;“Why, why, why?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were spoilt with three guests on day 4 (including Guss from RHoK, who’m I’d thought I’d serendipitously bumped into downstairs) and we mostly talked about how defining the real problem is critical and often difficult. Playing the “why?, why?,why?” game can help but often we must go further than that and question the very problem we are looking at or broaden our stakeholder group&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also discussed &lt;a href=&quot;http://launchvic.org/&quot;&gt;Launch Vic&lt;/a&gt; which invests in infrastructure for start-ups, things like promoting the building of co-working spaces, encouraging the expansion of capacity of existing places or investing in shared infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had our second challenge in what we thought was a PTV form redesign. I read the problem, and I read it again. I looked up at my colleges and shrugged. They looked at me and shrugged… We all read it again. Finally someone broke the awkward silence: “what’s wrong with that?”… “nothing” we all replied. It was then that we made the fatal mistake… we assumed the role of the customer… when the customer was about 150 meters away at the nearest train station! Had we consulted with our stakeholders they would have told us that all the problems we saw with the system were non-existent… although what do we do at that stage: the right answer (which one team did) is: pivot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me about three days to think of the perfect way to pivot that problem that still keeps it relevant to the problem that the seniors ticket is suppose to solve. One of the benefits of the program is to make travel at non-peak times more attractive to seniors and so reduce the load on public transport during peak times. So I would investigate the feasibility of providing seniors a more comprehensive package that included reduced fares for travelling in non-peak times during weekdays in addition to the free weekend pass, further driving down peak demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-5-retro&quot;&gt;Day 5: Retro&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote of the day: &lt;strong&gt;“As fast as things are now is as slow as they will ever be”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our final day we had a very enlightening discussion about the importance of designing with not only our users in mind but also the next generation. If our systems are to last they must be usable today and tomorrow… and tomorrow, that tomorrow might not look much like tomorrow does today&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also repeated the theme of finding the real problem, this time with an emphasis on visibility and making problems easy to find. Paint your problems red! There is also the possibility of using active agents to find problems, proactively creating autonomous entities that will seek out issues and conflicts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our teams also self formed on Friday and obviously I was in the TDF team. It was very interesting to see the self formation process. I’d love to tell you more but it’s all secret agile retro business (which might be beer if you go on the slack messages)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll finish on a photo of lunch time discussions at TeamSquare level 4 with a few people from the DTF!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codeforaustralia.github.io/DTF-Blog/images/DTF_lunch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary></summary></entry></feed>
